PATRICK HAZARD - CV

ABOUT ME

I'm a bit of geek in design. I love new technology and my interest in the web and apps have helped me push my knowledge in these areas. My current obsession is to improve my web knowledge and techniques. I am very quick to learn new skills and techniques and have the focus to teach myself anything I want to know. This has lead to me really being able to challenge myself as a designer and take on a lot of roles and responsibilities. After studying the basic design principles and techniques as a product designer, I have been working as a web and print graphic designer for over 5 years and feel very comfortable working for anything from marketing to front-end web development. My ambition is to learn more within these trades so I can move into a Creative/Marketing Planning role as my broad experience would suit the planning and orchestrating aspect of this type of position.

I love a challenge, in my job, through sports, and in life; most people just say I'm competitive. I love watching, playing and competing in most sports with a special interest in watersports. I feel experience in both team and endurance sports proves that I am great both working in a team and getting my head down as well as working and taking responsibility on my own. I decided to move to Perth as the outdoor lifestyle and atmosphere suit me perfectly so I'm now looking for the perfect job where I can grow and settle into life as an Australian.

If you want to find out more about me, you can contact me through my website hazardawareness.co.uk or email patrick@hazardawareness.co.uk

EXPERIENCE

Grass Roots Projectlink – October 2008 – October 2012

This role was a mixture of digital and print design for the Grass Roots Group. Through this role I got to work on projects for large multinational companies including RBS, Aviva and Renault. These projects involved work from brochures, posters to websites and html emails. I also worked with the consumer promotions side where I got to be more creative working for clients including Nestlé, Vodafone and Schwarzkopf. As this side is consumer based promotions, it involved a lot of advertising and marketing knowledge.

Due to the small size of our creative team, I have really had the opportunity to push myself into new design areas such as front end web development and flash work. I also got to work very closely with the Marketing side of the group for our and other companies marketing.

Haymarket Media – March 2007 – September 2007

Part of my university placement year was spent working at Haymarket in the Digital Media department working on their new corporate website. I was initially hired as a temp doing admin work, the creative director soon took me on as a freelance designer. This was my first commercial introduction to web technologies and digital design.

Cyclepods – September 2006 – March 2007

The other part of my placement year started as a 6 week Shell sponsored placement where I worked on developing an environmentally friendly cycle storage unit for schools. After doing so well during this, I was kept on to develop further projects in this cycle storage system. Although I really enjoyed this product design, I realised that I preferred the faster pace of graphic design e.g. the product brochure design.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Winner – Local Shell Step Most Enterprising Student 2006 Runner up – Regional Shell Step Most Enterprising Student 2006

Competing for GBR at the Age Group World and European Triathlon Championships

Although this isn't directly related to my design work, I am very proud of this and it really shows my dedication when I put my mind to something.

EDUCATION

Bournemouth University – BSc Product Design 2:1

Whilst this was a very challenging and interesting degree with an engineering focus that really suited me. It was here that I learned the basics of all design that allowed me to switch discipline to other areas of design.

Esher College

A's at A Level in Design, Maths and Physics, B at Geography AS Level